<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Blogfoolery</title>
        <link>http://hackfoolery.com</link>
        <description><![CDATA[RSS feed for hackfoolery.com/blog]]></description>
        <atom:link href="http://hackfoolery.com/rss.xml" rel="self"
                   type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 UT</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
    <title>utorrent-server on Arch Linux, via the AUR</title>
    <link>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-02-22-utorrent-sever-via-aur.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en-US">
	<head>
		<title>utorrent-server on Arch Linux, via the AUR</title>

		<meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=utf-8">

		<link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../css/mockup.css">

		<link rel="shortcut icon" href="../imgs/favicon.ico">
	</head>

	<body>
		<div id="content">

			<header>
				<a href="../">
					<img src="../imgs/logo.png" class="left" alt="hf logo" width="96" height="96">
				</a>
				<span class="page-title">
					<a href="../blog/index.html">blogfoolery</a>
				</span>
			</header>

			<hr>

			<section>

	<h1 class="headline">utorrent-server on Arch Linux, via the AUR</h1>
	<span class="meta">
		February 22, 2012<br />
		<a href="../me.html">Michael DeWitt</a>
	</span>
	
	<article>
		<p><em>This is a very crude guide to the Arch User Repository using utorrent-server as an example. The best place to learn about the AUR is on the <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/AUR">wiki page</a>. As this guide was written for a friend fairly new to linux and Arch Linux, it tries to assume very little about the reader’s knowledge of standard linux utilities or anything particular to Arch.</em></p>
<hr></hr>
<h1 id="installing">Installing</h1>
<p>Find the <a href="https://aur.archlinux.org/packages.php?ID=43253">AUR page</a> for utorrent-server. Download the tarball by clicking on the tarball link to the right of the PKGBUILD link and save it somewhere.</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="../imgs/aur-utorrent-server.png" alt="The AUR page for utorrent-server, with the Tarball link circled in red"></img><p class="caption">The AUR page for utorrent-server, with the Tarball link circled in red</p>
</div>
<h2 id="dependencies">Dependencies</h2>
<p>Before we attempt to build and install this package, we need to make sure that we have all of the required dependencies available on pacman or already installed. You could do this by reading the PKGBUILD and using <code>pacman -Ss &lt;package&gt;</code> for each package listed in the <code>depends</code> array near the top, where the search would return nothing if the package is in the AUR.</p>
<p>However, I find it much faster to just check the links on the AUR page for each of the packages listed as dependencies. When you mouseover each package, if the link displayed is to <code>www.archlinux.com/...</code>, the package is in pacman’s repositories. If it displays <code>aur.archlinux.com/...</code>, then you will need to install that package from the AUR first.</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="../imgs/aur-utorrent-server-dep-mouseover.png" alt="openssl-compatibility is an AUR package"></img><p class="caption"><code>openssl-compatibility</code> is an AUR package</p>
</div>
<p>In this case, <code>openssl-compatibility</code> is listed as a dependency and is an AUR package, so we’ll install it now. Follow the link there to its AUR page and download the tarball. (Save it in the directory that you put the utorrent-server tarball in when you downloaded it earlier.) This package has no dependencies, so we can go ahead with building and installing it.</p>
<p>In a terminal, move to the directory where you saved the tarball and unpack it with</p>
<pre><code>$ tar xzf openssl-compatibility.tar.gz</code></pre>
<p>In the above call to the <code>tar</code> utility, we pass it three options. <code>x</code> tells it that we are extracting something (as opposed to creating a tarball with <code>c</code>), <code>z</code> tells it to run the tarball through the <code>gunzip</code> command, which is required since this file is a gzipped file, and <code>f</code> tells it that the next argument following is the file to operate on.</p>
<p>When that is done, you will have a new directory named <code>openssl-compatibility</code>. Move into it and run</p>
<pre><code>$ makepkg -ic</code></pre>
<p>This command uses the PKGBUILD file in the current directory to download and build <code>openssl-compatibility</code> from its source files. In this case, we called it with two options following a single hyphen. <code>i</code> tells it to use <code>pacman -U</code> to install the local package file created by <code>makepkg</code>. This will prompt for the password for <code>sudo</code> and normal input for any installation with pacman. The second option passed to <code>makepkg</code>, <code>c</code>, tells it to remove unecessary source files after it is done building and installing the package. It will, however, keep the actual package file that was created in case you need to reinstall sometime.</p>
<p>(You may have noticed that when we passed options to <code>makepkg</code>, they had a hyphen in front of them, but for <code>tar</code> we left off the hyphen. <code>tar</code> is strange in that it, unlike most *nix utilities, doesn’t require a hyphen in front of its options if they are immediately after the call to tar, like the are above. You can include the hyphen like in <code>makepkg</code> and it will behave the same, but it is unecessary. It <em>must</em> be there for <code>makepkg</code> though.)</p>
<h2 id="the-actual-installation">The actual installation</h2>
<p>After this is done, the only remaining dependencies for utorrent-server should all be available in pacman repositories, so we can move back up a folder (<code>cd ..</code>) to where the utorrent-server tarball was saved. Unpack it</p>
<pre><code>$ tar xzf utorrent-server.tar.gz</code></pre>
<p>and move into the directory that creates (<code>cd utorrent-server</code>). Here, run</p>
<pre><code>$ makepkg -sic</code></pre>
<p>Note that a new option was used this time that was not used for openssl-compatibility. <code>s</code> tells <code>makepkg</code> to attempt to install all of the dependencies listed in the PKGBUILD required for installation and for building the package. If this were not used and some of the dependencies were not installed, <code>makepkge</code> would return an error and fail to build or install the package.</p>
<h1 id="running-utorrent-server">Running utorrent-server</h1>
<p>If you paid attention to the output of the last call to <code>makepkg</code> when we installed utorrent-server, it gave some short instructions for running the server. Namely, run</p>
<pre><code># /etc/rc.d/utorrent-server start</code></pre>
<p>This starts the daemon that runs the server in the background. If you want to stop or restart the server, run the same command, replacing start with stop or restart. (Since this is a daemon in Arch, you could also use <code>rc.d &lt;command&gt; utorrent-server</code> to start, stop, or restart the server. The two formats are equivalent.)</p>
<p>To actually use utorrent-server, you can open up a (javascript-enabled) browser and point it at <code>localhost:8080/gui</code> and be greated by a fairly familiar, if a bit laggy, interface to your favorite BitTorrent client from your Windows (or Mac) days. The rest should be pretty self-explanatory now that you have a gui. You can tweak settings, add torrents, and more from this interface and since it’s familiar, you should be downloading <del>movies</del> Linux ISOs in no time.</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="../imgs/utorrent-server-webgui.png"></img><p class="caption"></p>
</div>

		<p class="meta">Tags: <a href="../tags/archlinux.html">archlinux</a></p>

		<hr>

		<p>You've read this far? Read more articles like this one
		by clicking any of the tags above. <!--If you already have and
		really want to flatter me, click the RSS icon below and
		subscribe with your favorite RSS reader.--> Or, if you just
		scrolled all the way down here in search of a tl;dr, you might
		find my tweets more appealing,
		so choose the twitter
		icon.</p>
	</article>
</section>


			<hr>

			<footer>
				<nav class="left">
				  <a href="../">Home</a>
				| <a href="../code/index.html">Code</a>
				| <a href="../blog/index.html">Blog</a>
				| <a href="../me.html">Me</a>
				| <!-- <a href="/rss.xml">
				    <img src="/imgs/rss.png" class="nav-icon"></a> -->
				  <a href="https://twitter.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/twitter.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				  <a href="https://github.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/github-icon.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				</nav>

				<span class="right">
					Powered by <a href="http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll">Hakyll</a>
				</span>
			</footer>

		</div>
	</body>
</html>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-02-22-utorrent-sever-via-aur.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Contestron</title>
    <link>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-02-26-contestron.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en-US">
	<head>
		<title>Contestron</title>

		<meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=utf-8">

		<link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../css/mockup.css">

		<link rel="shortcut icon" href="../imgs/favicon.ico">
	</head>

	<body>
		<div id="content">

			<header>
				<a href="../">
					<img src="../imgs/logo.png" class="left" alt="hf logo" width="96" height="96">
				</a>
				<span class="page-title">
					<a href="../blog/index.html">blogfoolery</a>
				</span>
			</header>

			<hr>

			<section>

	<h1 class="headline">Contestron</h1>
	<span class="meta">
		February 26, 2012<br />
		<a href="../me.html">Michael DeWitt</a>
	</span>
	
	<article>
		<blockquote>
<p><em>“Contestron is alive. Contestron is watching. Contestron desires your correct and intelligent solutions.”</em><br> - Contestron: Helpful Information</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Every semester, IU Bloomington’s <a href="http://cs.indiana.edu/classes/c211">Introduction to Computer Science</a> holds a programming contest for all of the students taking the course. It consists of eight problems released one-by-one as the time limit (usually fifteen to twenty-five minutes) for the previous problem expires. All of the answers are written in Chez Scheme, the language of choice for the course.</p>
<p>The last problem for the Spring 2012 contest just expired a few hours ago, with my solution arriving with only a half a minute to spare. I had never done any programming contests before, but this seemed like the perfect time to start.</p>
<p><em>[Edit – 5 April 2012:<br /> You can now find <a href="https://github.com/mjdwitt/contestron">my Contestron solutions</a> hosted at my GitHub profile.]</em></p>
<hr></hr>
<p>I eagerly awaited the contest the entire week leading up to it, determined to win. Not only did I want to go head-to-head with my classmates, but I also had it from a reliable source on the school’s IRC channel that doing well would give me a leg up when I applied to become an undergraduate instructor for the course.</p>
<p>Luckily for me, I had chosen the lab section instructed by the senior CS student who had created the Contestron platform that served the problems and evaluated solutions for correctness. I took full advantage of this and made sure to ask him about what sorts of problems could be expected and which course-specific libraries we might be using in the contest. Not that Suzanne, our professor, had not described the problems we might be seeing; it just seemed a waste to pass up on an opportunity to find out more.</p>
<p>I awoke this morning a few minutes before my alarm—a recent habit I seem to have developed since moving to Bloomington in early January. Not willing to wait for the contest to begin, I immediately began working on other coding projects of my own until hunger finally forced me to get dressed and hunt down some breakfast. Needless to say, I was just a bit excited about Contestron.</p>
<p>One of my friends from high school who is also taking the course invited me to join him at a local coffee shop where he intended to take on Contestron with his laptop. While preparing mine for the contest back in my room, however, I found that the wireless drivers were acting up again and realized that I could not trust them to maintain a steady or even tenuous connection while submitting solutions on the contest’s site. This was probably for the best though; I much prefer working on my desktop with a full size keyboard and my custom XMonad setup.</p>
<p>About an hour before the contest began, I was refreshing the course website every five minutes looking for a post about where to find the contest. When the post arrived, I still had to wait another forty-five minutes first problem was released. After nervously flicking between various projects and time-killing websites, Contestron finally began with the first problem: a fifteen minute exercise in recursion over multiple lists.</p>
<p>According to my git logs, I finished the first exercise in about five minutes and then spent the remainder of the problem’s alloted time creating boilerplate comments for seven more problems. The second problem held a surprise: it came with an additional challenge problem which, while without impact on our standings in the contest, was irresistible. It seems that this challenge got the best of me, however; I committed the files for the second problem with a note that “2c is not quite right…”</p>
<p>As the third problem was released, I checked my record so far. My tests seemed to be all too correct; I had indeed missed the challenge. Luckily for my score, I had passed the others and thus had a perfect score on the problems that counted.</p>
<p>Problem three also came with a twist: it contained multiple parts and this time, none were optional. Similarly to its predecessors, it hinged on an understanding of recursion and lists while also testing the more recent course theme of modularity and encapsulation; the first part was meant as a sub-problem of the second.</p>
<p>It was at this point that my commits began slipping; the logs would not see another entry until the third through sixth problems were all committed at once. I certainly was no longer finishing in half of the time for each problem. In the midst of the growing stress, however, I received a text from my friend holed up in the coffee shop:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Did you see we were the two featured answers for problem 1?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I had been wondering why the blank space for sample solutions was not being filled immediately after a problem had closed. Apparently the professor and/or some TAs were going over our submitted solutions as soon as they were graded by Contestron and using that space for showcasing their favorites. This definitely seemed like good news for my future job prospects within the department.</p>
<p>The fourth problem was particularly memorable. While lacking any explicit mention of lists or recursion, it required us to compute the least common multiple of all the whole numbers up to a given number <code>n</code>. While it would have been fairly simple to brute-force the problem and test all the numbers greater than <code>n</code> until I found one divisible by all those from 1 to <code>n</code>, we were being graded on both our correctness <em>and</em> our style, so this did not seem to be appropriate.</p>
<p>Luckily for me, I have been studying <em>Real World Haskell</em> since I got it from my grandparents this past Christmas (thanks again!) and it has recently introduced me to the concept of using lists with built-in and proven concepts of recursion such as <code>map</code> and the various folds instead of hand-rolling an iterative function of my own which passes some sort of counter to each successive call. As it happened, these concepts worked beautifully in Scheme, which has its own <code>fold-right</code> function in addition to an extremely handy built-in for computing least common multiples, <code>lcm</code>.</p>
<table class="sourceCode scheme numberLines" startFrom="1"><tr class="sourceCode"><td class="lineNumbers"><pre>1
2
3
</pre></td><td class="sourceCode"><pre><code class="sourceCode scheme">(<span class="kw">define</span><span class="fu"> prob4</span>
  (<span class="kw">lambda</span> (n)
    (fold-right <span class="kw">lcm</span> <span class="dv">1</span> (range n))))</code></pre></td></tr></table>
<p>While I was unable to quickly find a function that would produce a list of the whole numbers up to <code>n</code> (I definitely missed Haskell’s curt <code>[1..n]</code> here) it was quick and simple to make my own <code>range</code> to substitute.</p>
<p>Four problems and two additional challenges later, each more difficult than the last, and I finished a twenty minute, two part exercise in barely enough time to calm down and go through the menus to upload my solution. I knew immediately that I had solved six of the eight graded problems correctly (and only one of the three challenges, unfortunately,) but it would be some time before the TAs could manually grade our style and announce the top three contestants. At this point, only the first four problems had revealed their featured solutions, so I took the time to lie down and calm my nerves. An hour later and the eighth problem and the challenge for the seventh still lacked their featured solutions—although I had also been featured in my solution for the sixth, an exercise in efficient and tail-recursive modular exponentiation.</p>
<p>Finally, after catching up on my backlog of articles I had emailed to my Kindle (my other awesome Christmas present, thanks Mom and Dad!) the top three places were announced: I had come in third.</p>
<p>While it was not the first place—or <em>Supreme Schemer</em>, as Suzanne enthusiastically calls it—I was quite happy with the results when I remembered that I had failed to solve two of the required problems before they expired. In the end, I learned that my hands sweat profusely while coding under stress and that I can maintain an adrenaline rush for a solid 150 minutes. I also learned that I should try and calm all of that adrenaline down next time, as all of my incorrect solutions failed tests due to trivial mistakes which I would have noticed easily had I been merely working on a homework assignment.</p>
<p>Most importantly, I learned that I definitely want to do more contests in the future. Now I can hardly wait until all of us in the CS club can decide what we want to do for our own contest this semester.</p>

		<p class="meta">Tags: <a href="../tags/iu.html">iu</a>, <a href="../tags/c211.html">c211</a>, <a href="../tags/scheme.html">scheme</a></p>

		<hr>

		<p>You've read this far? Read more articles like this one
		by clicking any of the tags above. <!--If you already have and
		really want to flatter me, click the RSS icon below and
		subscribe with your favorite RSS reader.--> Or, if you just
		scrolled all the way down here in search of a tl;dr, you might
		find my tweets more appealing,
		so choose the twitter
		icon.</p>
	</article>
</section>


			<hr>

			<footer>
				<nav class="left">
				  <a href="../">Home</a>
				| <a href="../code/index.html">Code</a>
				| <a href="../blog/index.html">Blog</a>
				| <a href="../me.html">Me</a>
				| <!-- <a href="/rss.xml">
				    <img src="/imgs/rss.png" class="nav-icon"></a> -->
				  <a href="https://twitter.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/twitter.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				  <a href="https://github.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/github-icon.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				</nav>

				<span class="right">
					Powered by <a href="http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll">Hakyll</a>
				</span>
			</footer>

		</div>
	</body>
</html>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-02-26-contestron.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Cross-training and shin splints</title>
    <link>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-04-09-crosstraining-and-shin-splints.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en-US">
	<head>
		<title>Cross-training and shin splints</title>

		<meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=utf-8">

		<link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../css/mockup.css">

		<link rel="shortcut icon" href="../imgs/favicon.ico">
	</head>

	<body>
		<div id="content">

			<header>
				<a href="../">
					<img src="../imgs/logo.png" class="left" alt="hf logo" width="96" height="96">
				</a>
				<span class="page-title">
					<a href="../blog/index.html">blogfoolery</a>
				</span>
			</header>

			<hr>

			<section>

	<h1 class="headline">Cross-training and shin splints</h1>
	<span class="meta">
		April  9, 2012<br />
		<a href="../me.html">Michael DeWitt</a>
	</span>
	
	<article>
		<p>While training for the <a href="http://www.hawthornhalfdayrelay.com/">Hawthorn Half Day</a> (HHD) last Spring, my brother Andrew and I learned a lot about willpower and ourselves harder mentally than we thought possible. This spring, however, as we train harder in an attempt to run over eighty miles between the two of us at the 2012 HHD, we are also learning about our physical growth limits and the importance of cross-training.</p>
<p>In the past week, I’ve had my first experience with injuries from a lack of cross-training. Seven days ago, I woke up with such a pain in my shins that I was barely able to walk for about an hour. It had happened eight days ago as well, but to a lesser extent that seemed normal for the morning after running over twenty miles. Four days later, I was still experiencing that pain, although it had abated some.</p>
<p>After talking with some other ultra runners, I learned that extreme shin splints like those I was experiencing were a common indicator of insufficient cross-training, especially among those that run in Vibrams as I do. Apparently the calve muscles will recover and grow stronger more easily than the much-smaller smaller muscles on the front of the shins. This leads to stress and swelling in the tendons on the front and, if ignored, can lead to stress fractures.</p>
<p>The same friends recommended that I try a simple routine<sup><a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1">1</a></sup> to bring the front of my shins up to strength as fast as possible. With luck, this should bring me back onto our training schedule in time to still make my goals for the HHD. If not, I’ve still got the eight hour solo ultra at the <a href="http://www.kennekuk.com/events.htm#Howl">Howl at the Moon</a> at the end of the summer.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr></hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>With your heels on the ground, lift your toes and the balls of your feet as high off the ground as you can and hold for ten to fifteen seconds, then relax for a few seconds. Repeat until the fronts of your shins are fatigued. Do this many time throughout the day to see faster improvement.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

		<p class="meta">Tags: <a href="../tags/running.html">running</a>, <a href="../tags/ultra.html">ultra</a></p>

		<hr>

		<p>You've read this far? Read more articles like this one
		by clicking any of the tags above. <!--If you already have and
		really want to flatter me, click the RSS icon below and
		subscribe with your favorite RSS reader.--> Or, if you just
		scrolled all the way down here in search of a tl;dr, you might
		find my tweets more appealing,
		so choose the twitter
		icon.</p>
	</article>
</section>


			<hr>

			<footer>
				<nav class="left">
				  <a href="../">Home</a>
				| <a href="../code/index.html">Code</a>
				| <a href="../blog/index.html">Blog</a>
				| <a href="../me.html">Me</a>
				| <!-- <a href="/rss.xml">
				    <img src="/imgs/rss.png" class="nav-icon"></a> -->
				  <a href="https://twitter.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/twitter.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				  <a href="https://github.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/github-icon.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				</nav>

				<span class="right">
					Powered by <a href="http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll">Hakyll</a>
				</span>
			</footer>

		</div>
	</body>
</html>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-04-09-crosstraining-and-shin-splints.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
    <title>New semester, new jobs, new hobbies</title>
    <link>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-09-02-new-semester-new-jobs-new-hobbies.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en-US">
	<head>
		<title>New semester, new jobs, new hobbies</title>

		<meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;charset=utf-8">

		<link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" href="../css/mockup.css">

		<link rel="shortcut icon" href="../imgs/favicon.ico">
	</head>

	<body>
		<div id="content">

			<header>
				<a href="../">
					<img src="../imgs/logo.png" class="left" alt="hf logo" width="96" height="96">
				</a>
				<span class="page-title">
					<a href="../blog/index.html">blogfoolery</a>
				</span>
			</header>

			<hr>

			<section>

	<h1 class="headline">New semester, new jobs, new hobbies</h1>
	<span class="meta">
		September  2, 2012<br />
		<a href="../me.html">Michael DeWitt</a>
	</span>
	
	<article>
		<p>After a mostly uneventful summer, I’m finally back in Bloomington for the new semester! Truthfully, I moved in nearly a month ago but these first few weeks have been crazy hectic as I began not only three new CS classes, but also two awesome new jobs. Despite the summer’s general banality, however, a couple things worth noting did take place: a wedding and a roadtrip.</p>
<p>Early in June, my older sister married her long-time girlfriend and fiancée. This being the first wedding of my siblings and my first as an adult, it was quite a different experience from those I attended when I was in elementary school. (Read: more fun, and even more intimidating.)</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="../imgs/kaitlyn-and-caitlin-freddie-mercury-victory.jpg" alt="The happy couple, with my sister channeling her inner Freddie Mercury."></img><p class="caption">The happy couple, with my sister <a href="http://i0.kym-cdn.com/photos/images/newsfeed/000/162/317/2vA1a.png">channeling her inner Freddie Mercury</a>.</p>
</div>
<p>Shortly before moving back to IU, I joined my brother, our best friend Eric, and a bunch of my brother’s climbing buddies on a road trip to go camping and climbing in Kentucky’s beatiful <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_River_Gorge">Red River Gorge</a>. Somewhere in the middle of all the sublime hiking and getting my ass kicked by the crags, I fell in love with the sport and promptly signed up for an indoor climbing class at IU as soon as I got back to a computer.</p>
<div class="figure">
<img src="../imgs/andrew-rat-stew.jpg" alt="My brother Andrew halfway up Rat Stew in Muir Valley"></img><p class="caption">My brother Andrew halfway up Rat Stew in Muir Valley</p>
</div>
<p>While that climbing class has been awesome so far, I’m even more excited to be back for my computer science classes. On the strong advice of Suzanne Menzel, my <a href="../tags/c211.html">C211: Introduction to Computer Science</a> instructor, I skipped one of the two courses typically taken in the second semester. As a result, I am shoehorning the remaining of the two—foundational computing theory—in with the standard third semster courses—a data structures and algorithms course in Java, and a systems class in which we explore a custom ARM setup in C and assembly.</p>
<p>As if I won’t be doing enough programming with that courseload, I’ve also started two new jobs this fall. The first is a volunteer position as an intern working for the School of Informatics and Computing’s <a href="http://serveit.soic.indiana.edu/aboutus.php">Serve IT</a> clinic, which does IT consulting for local non-profits. I’ll be working on the Special Ops team tackling several projects over the course of the semester<sup><a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1">1</a></sup>, beginning with implementing PHP templates for a new Drupal-based website for the Leadership Bloomington - Monroe County Alumni Association. Since I have no prior experience with Drupal or PHP, I’ve hit the ground running.</p>
<p>My second job (which actually pays!<sup><a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2">2</a></sup>) is working as an Undergraduate Instructor for C211. This position consists of teaching labs, grading labs and exams, holding office hours, and whatever else new Suzanne comes up with each week. I’m really looking forward to gaining new perspectives on programming from watching and helping the students in my sections work through their labs and homework.</p>
<p>I’ve been enjoying every minute of being back in Bloomington and all the chaos that comes with it this fall. We’ll see what sort of tune I’ll be singing when it all peaks come finals in three months, however.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr></hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Most Serve IT teams typically work with a single client agency over the course of a semester or longer on a specific project. The Special Ops team, however, works mostly on finishing previous projects and other projects with similarly accelerated schedules.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Okay, so these kind of positions are usually slave wages, but all it takes to keep me happy is enough for a new pair of Vibrams about once a year, entry fees for a race or two, and beer that’s worth drinking.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

		<p class="meta">Tags: <a href="../tags/iu.html">iu</a>, <a href="../tags/c211.html">c211</a>, <a href="../tags/serveIT.html">serveIT</a>, <a href="../tags/climbing.html">climbing</a>, <a href="../tags/wallOfText.html">wallOfText</a></p>

		<hr>

		<p>You've read this far? Read more articles like this one
		by clicking any of the tags above. <!--If you already have and
		really want to flatter me, click the RSS icon below and
		subscribe with your favorite RSS reader.--> Or, if you just
		scrolled all the way down here in search of a tl;dr, you might
		find my tweets more appealing,
		so choose the twitter
		icon.</p>
	</article>
</section>


			<hr>

			<footer>
				<nav class="left">
				  <a href="../">Home</a>
				| <a href="../code/index.html">Code</a>
				| <a href="../blog/index.html">Blog</a>
				| <a href="../me.html">Me</a>
				| <!-- <a href="/rss.xml">
				    <img src="/imgs/rss.png" class="nav-icon"></a> -->
				  <a href="https://twitter.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/twitter.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				  <a href="https://github.com/mjdwitt">
				    <img src="../imgs/github-icon.png" class="nav-icon"></a>
				</nav>

				<span class="right">
					Powered by <a href="http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll">Hakyll</a>
				</span>
			</footer>

		</div>
	</body>
</html>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://hackfoolery.com/blog/2012-09-02-new-semester-new-jobs-new-hobbies.html</guid>
</item>

    </channel> 
</rss>
